The Better Angels is a drama, history film directed by A.J. Edwards.
At an isolated log cabin in the harsh wilderness of Indiana circa 1817, the rhythms of love, tragedy, and the daily
hardships of life on the developing frontier shaped one of our nation’s greatest heroes: Abraham Lincoln.
Abe is a thoughtful and quiet boy who spends his days at the side of his beloved
mother while learning to work the land from his stern father.
When illness takes his mother, Abe's new guardian angel comes in the form of his new
stepmother, who sees the potential in the boy and pushes for his further education.
Sarah Lincoln, played by Diane Kruger.
Tom Lincoln, played by Jason Clarke.
Nancy Lincoln, played by Brit Marling.
Mr. Crawford, played by Wes Bentley.
Abraham Lincoln, played by Braydon Denney.
Dennis, played by Cameron Mitchell Williams.
The Better Angels is a 2014 American biographical historical drama film about
United States President Abraham Lincoln's formative years.
It was written and directed by A.
Edwards and produced by Terrence Malick.
The film had its premiere at 2014 Sundance Film Festival on January 18, 2014.
It was subsequently screened in the Panorama program at the 64th
Berlin International Film Festival on February 8, 2014.
In March 2014, Amplify acquired distribution rights to the film.
It was released on November 7, 2014.
The film explores themes of indiana, usa,
wilderness, education, biography, stepmother.
The tone is emotional.